

Andriamarolahy
RABETOKOTANY
Data Scientist

CONTACT

Website 🗞

arabetokotany@aimsammi.org

(+261) 0346171397 📞

Ambohibao-Antananarivo **Q**

LinkedIn in

Github 🕠

SKILLS

Math & Statistics ★★★★☆

Calculus Linear Algebra Statistical tests

Programming ***

Python Pandas Scikit-learn Tensorflow & Keras Pytorch Opencv

ML Methods ★★★☆☆

Regression
Classification
Ensemble methods
Neural Network
Deep Learning
Transfert learning
Clustering
Dimensionality reduction

Reinforcement learning

Analytics & Modeling *****

Data analysis

Model & Inference

Data Visualization ***

Matplotlib Seaborn Plotly Dash

PROFIL

Data Scientist with two years of experience in project work. Obtained a master's degree in Machine Intelligence from African Masters of Machine Intelligence Rwanda. Pioneered Al-powered products at Pulse. Skilled in Math & Statistics, Programming, Machine Learning Methods, Analytics & Modeling and Data Visualization.

WORK EXPERIENCE

R&D Scientist

Pulse Madagascar Jan 2021 – Current

- Created an Al-powered API to automatically extract personal information from the Malagasy ID card and international passport photos.
- Implemented various time series prediction techniques to predict server memory usage saturation to alert the IT manager.

Data science intern

Sonatel Senegal May 2018 - Nov 2018

- \bullet Finished a six-month internship at Sonatel with a distinction from my supervisor.
- Implemented CNN and OCR in order to digitize the ECOWAS ID card.

EDUCATION

Master's degree in Machine Intelligence

African Masters of Machine Intelligence (AMMI), Rwanda Sep 2019 - August 2021

- Majored in Machine Intelligence.
- Excelled in machine learning and data science coursework.
- \bullet Implemented transfert learning with the ResNet model to obtain the rank 7/36 in the kaggle "InClass Prediction Competition" for the classification of cassava diseases.
- Implemented the Support Vector Machine (SVM) model from scratch to obtain the rank 8/43 in the kaggle "InClass Prediction Competition" for DNA classification.
- Completed a final year project entitled "Evaluating Modern Unimodal Baselines for Visual Question Answering".

Master's degree in Mathematical Sciences

African Institute for Mathematical Sciences (AIMS), Senegal Sep 2017 - Feb 2019

- Majored in Big Data & Computer security.
- Excelled in big data and programming coursework.
- Completed an internship project at Sonatel Senegal, which consists in digitizing the ECOWAS ID card using OCR technique.
- Completed a final year project entitled "Robust Machine Learning With Imbalanced Data: Expanding Mixup".

AWARDS & CERTIFICATES

- Awarded a full scholarship from Google and Facebook for a master's program in artificial intelligence at the AMMI, Rwanda.
- Awarded a full scholarship for a master's program in mathematical sciences at the AIMS, Senegal.
- Received a certificate of completion from the "Software Engineering for Applied Mathematical Sciences (SEAMS 2018)" workshop held at the AIMS, South Africa.

OTHERS

- Languages: Malagasy (Native), English (Good command), French (Good command).
- Passions: Artificial Intelligence, New technologies.
- Activities: Learn foreign languages on Duolingo, read books, listen to music, football.